export const data= [
    {
        question: "Which of the following sorting algorithms typically performs better on nearly sorted arrays?",
        option1: "Quick sort",
        option2: "Merge sort",
        option3: "Bubble sort",
        option4: "Insertion sort",
        ans: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Given an array of integers, return indices of the two numbers such that they add up to a specific target. Example: Input: nums = [2, 7, 11, 15], target = 9, Output: [0, 1].Which of the following best describes the time complexity of solving the above problem using a brute-force approach?",
        option1: "O(1)",
        option2: "O(n)",
        option3: "O(n^2)",
        option4: "O(log n)",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "What is a disadvantage of using arrays in terms of memory management?",
        option1: "They allow for dynamic resizing",
        option2: "They are memory efficient",
        option3: "They may lead to wasted memory space if the array size is not optimized",
        option4: "They automatically handle memory deallocation",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "What is the time complexity of the optimal solution for finding the sum closest to the target?",
        option1: "O(n)",
        option2: "O(nlogn)",
        option3: "O(n^2)",
        option4: " O(n^3)",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "What is the time complexity of inserting an element at the end of a dynamic array when the array is full and needs to be resized?",
        option1:"O(1)",
        option2:"O(log n)",
        option3:"O(n)",
        option4:"O(n^2)",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: " Given an array of integers, move all the zeros to the end of the array while maintaining the relative order of the other elements.Example: Input: [0,1,0,3,12], Output: [1,3,12,0,0].Which of the following data structures can be used to efficiently solve the problem of moving zeros to the end of the array?",
        option1: "Stack",
        option2: "Queue",
        option3: " Linked list",
        option4: "Two-pointer technique",
        ans: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Rotate an array to the right by k steps, where k is non-negative.Example: Input: nums = [1,2,3,4,5,6,7], k = 3, Output: [5,6,7,1,2,3,4].What is the time complexity of the optimal solution for rotating an array by k steps?",
        option1: "O(1)",
        option2: "O(n)",
        option3: "O(nlogn)",
        option4: "O(k)",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "Given an array nums of n integers and an integer target, find three integers in nums such that the sum is closest to target. Return the sum of the three integers.Example: Input: nums = [-1,2,1,-4], target = 1, Output: 2 (Explanation: The sum that is closest to the target is 2. (-1 + 2 + 1 = 2).).What is the time complexity of the optimal solution for finding the sum closest to the target?",
        option1: "O(n)",
        option2: "O(nlogn)",
        option3: " O(n^2)",
        option4: "O(n^3)",
        ans: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Given an array of integers, move all the zeros to the end of the array while maintaining the relative order of the other elements.Example: Input: [0,1,0,3,12], Output: [1,3,12,0,0]",
        option1: "Two-pointer technique",
        option2: "Queue",
        option3: "Linked list",
        option4: "Stack",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "what is the time complexity of merge sort?",
        option1: "O(n)",
        option2: "O(nlogn)",
        option3: "O(n^2)",
        option4: "O(n^3)",
        ans: 2,
    },
];